nei.org 2017-01-28

# NEI site - Nuclear Energy Institute

**NEI Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected from users of NEI websites (“you” or “users”).  NEI currently collects several types of information from online users, including personal information that you voluntarily submit on publication order forms, meeting registration forms, newsletter or update service subscription forms, e-mails sent to NEI, or member registration forms and other information submitted for access to the Member Center section on our website.

To improve our website and services, we may automatically collect information when you visit, such as IP address or other unique device identifier; details about your browser, operating system, and hardware; any referring URL; and other logging information, such as the date and time of your visit and your activities on our website.  We also use technologies such as cookies, clear-gifs, and web beacons to collect information about website usage and any preferences that you set, so that we may customize your experience and further improve our services.

We use third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, that may track details about your online activities over time and across different sites.  These services provide demographic and user profiling information, and help us to improve our website and outreach services.  These analytics tools and services may also allow us and others to provide you with targeted advertisements or other content that you may be interested in based on your online activities.  You can learn more about Google Analytics and privacy [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html) and your choices about Google ad settings [here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

**Personal Information:   **Personal information that you voluntarily disclose to NEI either online or in writing through publication order forms, meeting registration forms, survey response forms, service enrollment or registration forms, or e-mail sent to NEI, is added to the relevant NEI database to enable our processing of orders or registration, to update our databases, to enable us to make appropriate responses, and to allow us to analyze and improve our efforts.  This information usually includes name, e-mail and/or physical address, item or service purchased or requested, meeting attended, or topic of interest, and may include credit card data if you place an order online.

NEI may send e-mails or other communications to you based on the information that you voluntarily submit to us.  On occasion, we also contract with third parties for co-marketing or other activities related to our goals and objectives, and allow them to use selected member or user information under strict confidentiality agreements.  NEI does not otherwise rent or sell e-mail addresses submitted to us.  NEI will not otherwise disclose its member or customer information to the government or other third parties, unless required by law.

Information provided to NEI in non-electronic form may also be used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.  Individuals who would like to “opt out” of receiving additional communications from NEI should contact us to have their names removed from our lists. Corrections or other changes may also be made by contacting us using the information below.

NEI endeavors to take appropriate measures to assure the reliability of member records and to protect the personal information that we collect from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, or alteration.  We use commercially reasonable technologies, security measures, and other safeguards to protect member records and other personal information that we collect.

**Cookies:   **We may use cookies to enhance your experience with our website. "Cookies" are small files downloaded to your device that enable your browser to save and recall information about your use of the NEI website, such as the web pages you visited, the date when you last looked at a specific web page, and specific preferences you record.  We may use this data to tailor your experiences, to show you content that we think you may be interested in, and to customize content according to your preferences.  Although you can prevent websites from placing cookies on your computer by using your browser's preference menu, disabling cookies may affect your ability to use all the features of our website.

**Public Forums:   **NEI may make chat rooms, forums, or message boards available to its online users.  Please remember that any information that you disclose in these areas becomes public and is not considered to be personal information, regardless of the content.  Please exercise caution when deciding what information to disclose in such forums.

**Third Party Sites & Services:  **We may provide links or other features that allow you to access content or use third party services, such as social media, on our website.  Such services and content are subject to their own privacy policies, and you should review them prior to use.

**Personal Information Transferred to the United States:**  Our organization and website are located in the United States.  The privacy and data protection laws in other areas may be different.  By using our website, you consent to our transferring the personal information that we collect to the United States for processing and use as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Children’s Privacy:**  We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent, and if we become aware that we have collected such information, we will delete it.  If you have reason to believe that we may have collected personal information from a child under 13, please contact us immediately using the information below.

**Changes and Amendments to this Privacy Policy:   **NEI reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time, by posting amended terms on this website.  Your use of our website after the effective date constitutes acceptance of the amended policy.  We reserve the right to apply the amended terms to the information that we have already collected, subject to any legal constraints. You should read and review this page regularly to see if there have been any changes.

**Successors and Legal Obligations:   **NEI reserves the right to provide any successor in interest with our member and user database, and other information collected pursuant to this Privacy Policy.  We also reserve the right to comply with court orders or other legal obligations.

**Contact Information:   **If you have any questions, concerns or requests related to our privacy policy, please contact us at membership@nei.org or by calling NEI Member Services at (202) 739-8000.

**Effective Date:   **The effective date of this Privacy Policy is May 2, 2014.
